那不是你父亲吗?
Isn't that your father?
他给洛伦佐当公证人
He serves as Lorenzo's notary.
离美第奇家族远点 莱昂纳多
Stay away from the Medicis, Leonardo.
如果您能把您的存款从美第奇银行
If you transfer your accounts to the Pazzi Bank,
转到帕吉银行里来 您就能获得充足的资金
away from the Medicis, you'll have all the funds you need.
几乎感觉不到疼痛
Its bite is almost never noticed.
不会有证据指向洛伦佐的爱人
So no evidence implicating Lorenzo's lover.
我能再为您做模特吗?
May I model for you again?
想推销商品去博蒂切利那边吧 他容易上当
Go peddle your wares with Botticelli. He's an easy mark.
提审这里提到的人 队长
Interrogate the victim mentioned here, Captain.
他只要认罪 就逮捕他
Once he confirms the charges, make your arrest.
此事已经引起了值夜的官员注意
It has come to the attention of the Officers of the Night,
是通过匿名告发的方式
by means of secret denunciation,
有一位叫莱昂纳多・达芬奇的人
Leonardo di ser Piero da Vinci
被认定犯有鸡奸罪
has committed the grievous act of sodomy.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：潇妹纸
时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：竺 浅浅 碟子
校对：竺 影子
达芬奇的恶魔 第一季第5集
不是做梦 你还在这里
Weren't no dream. You're still here.
为什么我们要跟掏粪的关在一起?
Why do we have to share cells with a dung puncher?
他睡得像婴儿一样沉 我都不敢翻身了
He's sleeping like a baby, I'm scared to turn over.
蝙蝠
Bats.
那是什么地方?
What is that place?
单人禁闭室 专关那些不服管的人
Solitary confinement, where we put the troublemakers.
你最好老实点
So behave yourself.
那有蝙蝠的窝吗?
The bats nest in there?
上百个呢 跟粪坑一样
By the hundreds. It's a shit-hole.
所以没准你喜欢呢
Then again, maybe you'd like it.
你那个姓美第奇的朋友呢?
Where's your Medici friend now?
尊敬的阁下
Your Highness.
这里是我们运行的心脏
The beating heart of our operation.
好 工作人员还真多
Yes. With an impressively large workforce.
我数数 三 五 七...
Let me see. Three, five, seven...
13个... 27个...
13... 27...
阁下
Your Highness.
试试你的人抗干扰能力而已
Just testing the mettle of your men.
而且我肯定你已知晓 伊莎贝拉女王和我
As I'm sure you're aware, Queen Isabella and I,
不是随便选择银行的
don't offer our business to just anyone.
我给你的保证不止来自我们工作人员的能力
I can assure you not only of the competency of my men,
而且还来自我们这全欧洲
but also guarantee our reputation
最有信用银行的信誉
as the most trusted bank in all of Europe.
不过你们不再是教皇的银行了
And yet you no longer serve as God's banker.
这只是暂时的
Well, for now.
原因在于与罗马现在的政见不合
A disagreement with the current policies in Rome.
我相信教皇很快会醒悟的
One I pray God will soon see rectified.
那位我听说被你们
Do you deserve God's favor,
高度称赞的艺术家如此表现 还能受到教皇的眷顾吗?
given the behavior of this artist I hear you hold in high regard?
达芬奇的表现和命运我都不关心
Neither Da Vinci's actions nor his fate are my concern.
我只关心我们的合作
Only our business together is.
我想要的只是一个机会
All I ask is for the opportunity to show you,
向你展示美第奇家族的能力
what the Medicis are capable of.
我好奇
I'm curious.
罗马大概...
Approximately how many florins did...
提走了多少钱?
Rome actually default on?
截止到上个月 总数为八万七千弗罗林
As of last month, the sum stood at 87,000 florins.
我了如指掌
I never lose count.
我的人都如此
Nor do my men.
美第奇家族一直都是艺术的支持者
The Medici family have always been patrons of the arts.
特别是那些颂扬神圣的
Particularly those celebrating the holy faith.
这件艺术品最明显了 殿下
Which is distinctly true of this creation, Your Highness.
多纳泰罗雕刻的大卫
David, as sculpted by Donatello.
把我从狮熊爪下救出的主啊
The Lord who saved me from the claws of the lion and the bear,
也会救我远离这龌龊
will save me from this abomination.
您难道看不出其中的美感吗 托克马达修士?
You do not see beauty in its design, Friar Torquemada?
我听说你们这儿的艺术家
Is the artist a sexual deviant,
都有性怪癖 这个也一样吗?
like others I've heard of in this region?
我觉得很下流
I find it lewd.
我们走之前请把它盖起来吧
Please cover it for the remainder of our visit.
听我的 小子
Here's how it works, boy.
你把吃的给我 我就不把你脑袋摁到肚子里去了
You feed me, I don't stave your head in.
还给他
Give it back.
你想怎么样啊 小书生?
What are you gonna do about it, scribbler?
我会抢回来
I'm gonna take it off you.
现在呢?
What about now?
行了! 分开!
Come on! Break it up!
现在怂了吧!
Not so confident now!
按你要求... 给你的食物
Your food... as requested.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
洛伦佐要你来救我
Lorenzo asked you to save me.
你不可能在庭上见到洛伦佐 也不能怪他
You will not see Lorenzo in court and you cannot blame him for that.
你的辩方只有我一个
Your defense rests solely with me.
- 我建议...  - 认罪?
- I advise...  - Pleading guilty?
- 很不幸 是的  - 很不幸 是的
- Unfortunately, yes.  - Unfortunately, yes.
我觉得这是你唯一的出路
I see this as your only option.
如果你够幸运 可以免除腐刑
If you're lucky, you may escape castration.
不! 不
No! No.
不认罪 不妥协
No, pleas. No bargains.
我要申诉所有的罪名
I want full refutation of the charges.
不... 我要让他们撤诉
No... I want them dropped.
我还因为某些未知的诉方被关在这里
I remain locked in here on the accusations of some unknown accuser.
- 不重要  - 不重要吗?
- Unimportant.  - Unimportant?
除非你能提供对鸡奸
Unless you can provide an alibi against the accusation
这位雅各布・沙特瑞里罪名的...
that you sodomized one...
不在场证明
Jacopo Saltarelli.
雅各布不是受害人
Jacopo's no victim.
我们有些理由可以找
We have a number of defenses at our disposal.
- 酗酒...  - 不
- We can blame drink...  - No.
吸食鸦片
The use of opiates.
或者我们可以平摊罪责
Or we can shift blame.
比如你的导师为洛奇奥
Your mentor Verrochio, perhaps.
是他把你惯坏了
He corrupted you as a boy,
扭曲了你的道德观
warping your sense of morality.
你敢再扯远点吗? 就说都是拜你所赐
Why not go further back? Claim it began with you.
哦 该死! 我特别强调要一颗古巴雨林葡萄!
Oh, fuck! I specifically asked for Marcgravia Evenia!
啊 在这
Ah, here it is.
你是要吃还是要玩啊?
Are you gonna eat them or play with them?
- 我会没收的  - 好 随意
- I'll confiscate them.  - Yeah. By all means.
向所有人证明我用片树叶也能威胁到你
Demonstrate to everyone that I can terrify you with a leaf.
没准我能挖个地道逃跑呢
Perhaps I can dig an escape tunnel.
你挖地道的日子已经远去了 鸡奸犯
Your tunneling days are over, sodomite.
这得看你怎么看待性怪癖了
Deviance is in the eye of the beholder.
植物就演示了一种 授粉
Plants practice a form of it. Pollination.
他们吸引蜜蜂 蝙蝠 来帮它们传粉
They seduce bees, bats, into transporting their seed.
因为蝙蝠通过回声来飞行
Because bats use echo to navigate.
看到了吗?
See?
植物就长出了利用的办法
Plants have devised a way to exploit it.
一般的叶子 回声很小
Cos normal leaves, they have weak reflections.
不过这些凹形的花瓣 它们...
But these concave petals, they...
把声音反射到更大的范围内
they reflect sound over a much larger area.
就像洞穴一样
Like a cave.
吸引蝙蝠前来 就像双方同意的协约一样
And it draws the bats in. It's a consensual arrangement.
蝙蝠吃到花蜜而花朵得以授粉
The bats get nectar and the flowers get sex.
精神错乱 当然 也可以让我们拿来当做理由
Insanity is, of course, another defense at our disposal.
如果你认为这些指控会凭空消失 说明你真的是疯了
You are demented if you think these charges will simply vanish.
必须消失
They must.
会消失的
They will.
那个铁面的村姑根本就不懂艺术
That pan-faced wench wouldn't know art if it sat on her face,
而且肯定跟她的修士有关
which her friar clearly longs to do.
而且 失去罗马的业务
And yet, having lost Rome's business,
我们对斐迪南和伊莎贝拉的需要比他们对我们的需要大得多
we need Ferdinand and Isabella far more than they need us.
斐迪南提到庭审的事了吗?
Did Ferdinand mention the trial?
当然提了
Of course he did.
罗马使用这些指控的策略很明智
Rome's strategy with these charges is brilliant.
他们来的时机很不凑巧
They couldn't have come at a worse time.
斐迪南和伊莎贝拉也有自己的难处
Ferdinand and Isabella face their own difficulties.
他们现在正跟葡萄牙开战
Currently they wage war with Portugal,
国内还有内战
while facing civil uprisings at home.
也许他们是需要分散一下压力
Perhaps what they require is distraction.
你觉得什么东西最能让他们高兴?
And what exactly do you think would amuse them?
篝火晚会?
A bonfire of Jews?
让你弟弟决定吧
Let your brother decide that.
他可以安排一场演出
He can create a theatrical spectacle,
到处都是高兴的市民
fill the stands with happy citizens,
展示一座和谐的城市
and show a harmonious city.
你疯了? 把我们的命运交到朱利亚诺那双笨手里去?
Are you mad? Put our faith in Giuliano's clod-hopping hands?
跟你一样 他有他自己的天赋
Like you, he has his talents.
你有感染力 他有魅力
You impress. He charms.
他看起来糟透了 里面给他东西吃吗?
He looks like hell. Do they feed him in there?
治安官 辩方准备就绪了
Magistrate, the defense is prepared.
诉方还来吗?
Will the prosecution be joining us?
还是他们已经意识到都是谬诉?
Or have they realized the error of these charges?
你的答案到了
Your answer has arrived.
弗朗西斯科・帕吉到底来干什么? 他不是公证人
What the hell is Francesco Pazzi doing here? He's not a jurist.
这对达芬奇有利 不是吗?
That's good for Leo, isn't it?
帕吉家是美第奇家的宿敌
Pazzis are the Medicis' rivals.
治安官 我能不能指出帕吉先生出席这次庭审有些不妥?
Magistrate, may I raise a point relating to Signor Pazzi's role in this trial?
就我所知 他不是公证人之一
To my knowledge, he is not a member of the Notary Guild.
帕吉阁下的合作身份
Signor Pazzi's associate membership,
已于昨晚的即席会议上批准了
was approved at an impromptu session last night.
是提出反对的恰当方式
Which was the appropriate forum for raising any objections.
你要代表你儿子提出正式的申诉吗?
Do you wish to make a formal complaint on behalf of your son?
他不是...
He's not...
不
No.
不申诉
No complaint.
被告要请求减刑吗?
Does the accused have any opening mitigation to enter into plea?
请求 我们要对所有的指控提出辩护
May it please the court, we will be contesting all the charges.
达芬奇先生 你知道藐视法庭
Signor Da Vinci, do you understand the potential ramifications
可能带来的后果吗?
of challenging these indictments?
我的当事人要求公开声明的特权
My client requests the privilege to make an opening statement.
我已经将我的生命...
I have dedicated my life...
贡献于对自然的研究...
to the study of nature...
远离迷信和歪曲
free from superstition or distortion.
这些指控 往好里讲
These accusations, at best,
是源于无知愚昧
stem from a wellspring of ignorance.
往差里讲 通过这种方式
And, at worst, it speaks of political chicanery,
拷问一个人的社会关系 就是政治欺骗
to question anyone's intimate relations in this manner,
因为我没有任何羞愧之事
cos I have nothing to be ashamed of.
也没有什么要辩护的
And I have nothing to defend.
我可以担保 应该让我上去的
I can vouch for that. Should put me on the stand.
听他如何玷污了一个人没用
Hearing how he deflowered a nun won't help.
顶多就是罚款 这个罪名不会判火刑的
He'll only receive a fine. No-one burns for this any more.
那些永远不可能出生的生命
Of those who will never be born,
都是拜他们所赐
thanks to their vice.
你们城市里的鸡奸犯...
The sodomites in your city...
背负着那些无法出生的灵魂
have the souls of the unborn on their conscience.
那些灵魂呼唤着公正
Those souls scream for justice.
"火刑
"To the fire.
火刑!"
To the fire!"
反而 你们的领袖对鸡奸犯
Instead, your leaders promote sodomy,
只征收罚金 而不使用适当的制裁
by levying fines instead of the proper sanction,
那就是... 火刑
which is... the fire.
是有人往他酒里拉屎了吗?
Who shat in his wine sack?
若是对罪行征税 那就是创造了一项商品
When you tax a crime, you make it a commodity.
美第奇家族从他人的犯罪中获利
The Medicis make their fortune from this vice
代价是给佛罗伦萨留下了永久的耻辱
at the price of Florence's eternal shame.
反对 治安官 我实在无法理解一个外国人
Objection, Magistrate. I cannot comprehend why a foreigner
凭什么在此作证
is being allowed to testify here today.
我传尊敬的托克马达修士来此 是作为道德证人
I called the esteemed Friar Torquemada as a voice of morality,
提醒在场诸位 上帝加诸给我们的神圣责任
reminding us all of our solemn responsibilities before God.
难道你要否认他的这项权利?
Would you deny him that right?
我只想提醒法庭 这些指控的严重性当然毋庸置疑
I would only remind the court that the seriousness of these charges is not in doubt,
但上帝并不赞同我们惩罚无辜
but God is not served by punishing the innocent.
案件仍然有足够的诉由
The case remains to be made.
既然如此... 先休庭吧
Then perhaps it shall... after a recess.
虽然身在这里 不过我听说
I've heard, through the prison grapevine,
朱利亚诺准备给伊莎贝拉夫妇安排一场戏剧演出
that Giuliano's mounting a theatrical production for the royal couple.
你现在面临长期关押 可能会被判处宫刑
You face prolonged captivity and possible gelding,
你居然还关注这种无关紧要的小事
yet your thoughts focus on trivialities.
把这个交给琐罗亚斯德
See this is delivered to Zoroaster.
你写的这些都是胡言乱语
All you wrote was gibberish.
坐牢影响了你的思维
Your imprisonment affects your mind.
有可能 不过那是密码
That's perhaps true, but that's cipher.
如果他们还要继续关押我
If my internment is to continue,
我有些私人事情要处理
then there are certain private wishes I need fulfilled.
都是小事 处理一下我的生意
Minor matters. Disposition of my business.
没别的
That's all.
不用您操心 父亲
It's nothing to trouble you, Father.
哦 嗯...
Oh, um...
如果朱利亚诺还没选好剧本的话
If Giuliano is yet to select a text,
我建议选"十日谈"吧
may I suggest the Decameron.
我最喜欢那个"失窃的猪"的故事
My favorite is the stolen pig story.
很能取悦观众的
It's quite a crowd-pleaser.
那... "耶稣受难记"呢?
What about... a Passion Play?
进行两小时的道德教学吗? 不行
Two hours of moral instruction? No.
要找一个更具有娱乐性的
I need a more diverting theatrical piece
分散对那起小丑闻的注意力
to distract the royals from our little scandal.
- "俄狄浦斯"?  - 不 我觉得不好
- Oedipus Rex?  - No, I think not.
乱伦比鸡奸也好不到哪去
We'd just be trading sodomy for incest.
我一直很喜欢"利西翠妲"
I've always loved Lysistrata.
什么? 讲女性性罢工的那部?
What? Women withholding sex?
那部戏多恐怖 而且伊莎贝拉本身就...
Not only is that terrifying, but Isabella is...
性冷淡
well, frigid.
我们还是不要引起这个话题
We probably shouldn't draw attention to it.
那演"鸟"吧 殿下?
The Birds, then, Excellency?
一个幻想故事 还有好听的歌曲
A fantasy with pleasing songs.
听着就很无聊
Sounds boring as shit.
我儿...
My s...
被告让我把这个交给你
defendant asked me to deliver this.
是用一些鬼密码写的
It's in some blasted code,
不过依我看 不是他的遗愿或遗嘱
but as far as I can see, it's not his last will and testament.
安德里亚 我是来咨询你艺术家的专业意见的
I came to you for your artistic expertise, Andrea.
你有没有好建议?
Do you have nothing suitable to offer?
您有没有考虑过"十日谈"?
Have you considered the Decameron?
没有 该考虑它吗
No. Should we.
是讽刺题材的 十分风趣幽默 而且是佛罗伦萨人写的
It's a satire, brilliantly funny and penned by a native son of Florence.
当然也包含部分涉及性的内容
With quite a bit of sex in it.
- 男女之间的性事吧?  - 那当然
- Between a man and a woman?  - Of course.
那我觉得没问题 就选它了
Well, I don't see the problem. We have our choice.
- 给我准备剧本  - 殿下 这样好吗?
- Bring me a transcription.  - Is this wise, Excellency?
难道我们不用再审查一下"十日谈"的内容?
Wouldn't it be better to examine the Decameron again?
我听说"失窃的猪"那段很能取悦观众的
I'm told the stolen pig is quite a crowd pleaser.
先生 又开庭了
Signor, court has been recalled.
沙特瑞里先生... 我问你
Tell me... Signor Saltarelli,
你回到达芬奇先生的工作室的时候
when you went back to Signor da Vinci's studio,
发生了什么事?
what happened?
大师说要给我画一幅画 裸体画
The Maestro offered to draw me. Naked.
你也给别的画家做过模特
You've modeled for other artists before,
所以这也没什么不寻常
so this wasn't unusual.
那他给你付报酬了吗?
Did he pay you for your time?
付了
Yes.
四个金弗罗林
Four gold florins.
一晚上就挣了这么大一笔
A handsome sum for an evening's work.
这可是一般劳工一个月才能挣到的数量
The laborer would have to toil for a month to earn the same.
这笔钱不仅是做模特的报酬吧?
The payment wasn't just for the drawing, was it?
不是
No.
- 是我的封口费  - 封口费?
- It was for my silence.  - Your silence?
什么秘密能值上四个金弗罗林的价钱?
What secret requires a payment of four gold florins?
他强迫我肛交
He sodomized me.
对他这可憎的行为 你表示了同意
Did you consent to this heinous act,
或者给他了任何暗示 鼓励什么的吗?
offer any encouragement whatsoever?
没有 先生 完全没有
No, Sir. None.
所以是莱昂纳多・达芬奇强迫你的?
So Leonardo da Vinci forced himself on you?
你这是第一次... 被强奸?
This was your first time... being raped?
是的
Yes.
所以你受了巨大的伤害
And you were so traumatized,
- 你不得不立刻跑出去大肆庆祝了一番?  - 我反对!
- you went out and celebrated immediately after?  - I object!
你当晚没有出现在"犬吠"酒吧
Were you not at the Barking Dog that evening,
替全店的人买单吗?
buying drinks for the establishment's entire clientele?
有
Yes.
我需要麻醉我的痛苦
I needed something to numb the pain.
需要有朋友的陪伴
To be surrounded by friends.
前面还是后面?
Front or back?
我的当事人是从前面还是后面强暴你的?
Did my client take you from the front or the back?
- 都有  - 多少次呢?
- Both.  - How many times?
- 三次  - 肯定很痛吧
- Three.  - It must have been painful.
但是你不寻求治疗 反而去狂欢
And yet you chose revelry over medical aid.
太过分了! 这个小男孩不应该在这遭受这种耻辱
Outrageous! This boy's not the one who should suffer humiliation.
- 那我当事人受的耻辱呢?  - 那个由我来决定
- What of my client's suffering?  - I will decide.
你想和你儿子一起被关押吗?
Do you want to join your son in the Bargello?
你再这么问下去 你就要和你儿子作伴了
Because that's the way you're heading with this line of questioning.
被告方应该有权利追问案件的每个细节
The defense must be allowed to pursue all aspects of the case.
- 你儿子有罪  - 案子还没审完呢
- Your son is guilty.  - The case is not complete.
这场审判只是一场表演 蠢货
This trial is a performance, you oaf.
就像美第奇赞助的面包和马戏
Like the bread and circuses of your Medici sponsor.
现在 演好你那部分戏 否则你就是多余的
Now, play your part and perhaps you will be spared.
抱歉
I apologize
我挑起了不愉快的回忆
for dredging up what must be uncomfortable memories.
先生 这是你的本职工作而已
You were only performing your job, Signor.
你是做什么工作的?
And what of your job, hm?
你是怎样靠我当事人给你的金弗罗林
How do you survive beyond the gold florins
糊口度日的?
my client allegedly gave you?
当然仅靠兼职模特是不够的
Surely not on the occasional modeling assignment.
- 达芬奇先生  - 也许你的沉默
- Signor Da Vinci.  - Perhaps your silence
是因为你不想承认你在经营卖淫业务
is because you would prefer not to admit to your true profession of prostitution.
- 反对!  - 你今天的表演收到了多少报酬?!
- Objection!  - How much are you being paid for your performance today?!
- 够了!  - 哈哈!
- Enough!  - Ha-ha!
现在休庭...
The court is adjourned...
我要为辩护方想一个合理的刑罚
so I may consider suitable punishment for defense council.
你对做事很有一套啊
You're quite good at this.
我不是为了你做的
I didn't do that for you.
你的行为令我恶心
You disgust me.
从谎言中可以看出 那男孩的部分供词是真实的
Through the lies, some part of that boy's story is true.
我警告过你 别太嚣张了
I warned you, Leonardo, about overreaching.
你曾经把生活当成游戏
You have thought life a game,
但罗马的宠物狗已经控制了你的命运
but Rome's lapdogs have already decided your fate.
他们控制了舆论后
And when they have swayed the crowd,
他们会让你在监狱里慢慢腐烂死去
they'll leave you to rot in your cell
直到你的仅剩的一点感觉都被吃光
until your already-diminished senses are all but eaten away.
那个男婊子演砸了
That hustler hurt us.
如果人们相信他这个不是道德问题
If the people believe he's amoral,
即使没有贿赂 我也可以通过有罪判决
I can't pass a guilty verdict without appearing corrupt myself.
你会按命令行事
You'll do as instructed.
我是选举出来的法官
I'm an elected official.
我只做有回报的工作
I'll do as someone pays me to do.
别着急
Don't fret.
你孙子的竞选会获得瑞阿里奥伯爵的赞助
Count Riario's coin will fund even your grandson's campaign for this office.
塞翁失马焉知非福
Perhaps this setback's a blessing.
这场诉讼拖得越久
The longer we draw out these proceedings,
洛伦佐的公众形象只会更尴尬
the more we embarrass Lorenzo in the public eye.
达芬奇在牢房里困得越久
And the longer Da Vinci rots in his cell,
他的思想就会越来越混乱 负罪感就越重
the more his mind frays and the guiltier he looks.
队长
Captain.
先生?
Signor?
让大家集合吧
Gather your men.
这不是购物单 这只是些废话
This isn't a shopping list. It's just nonsense.
别浪费你的时间 他这是用暗语写的
Don't waste your time. He wrote it in cipher.
是张清单 还为之前
A list of items, precise instructions
在美第奇庆功会上冷落我而郑重道歉
with an absence of an apology for snubbing me at the Medici celebration.
镁 达芬奇大师想要这个来做什么?
Magnesium. What does Maestro Da Vinci want with this?
我如果知道就惨了 不要说他的名字 不然会被当成同伙
Fucked if I know. But don't speak his name unless you'd like to join him.
做什么都好 为什么要鸡奸?
Of all things, why sodomy?
我的意思是 没有人这样做过
I mean, no-one gets tried for that.
是的 在佛罗伦萨没有人做过
Yeah, not in Florence.
向任何一个方向走100英里 你会发现罗马严格控制着你的性行为
Go 100 miles in any direction and suddenly Rome owns your prick.
你们没权在这里搜查!
You have no right to be here!
这里肯定有证据! 继续搜!
There must be something here! Keep searching!
- 你们在干什么?  - 搜查
- What are you doing?  - Look over there.
- 搜查什么?  - 证据... 关于达芬奇到底是什么人
- Look for what?  - Evidence... of who Da Vinci truly is.
长官 找到一个有更多日记的秘密隔间
Sir. Found a hidden compartment with more journals.
队长 看看这个
Captain, look at this.
这就是帕吉要的
This is what Pazzi wants.
深入调查莱昂纳多・达芬奇
Further investigation into Leonardo Da Vinci
已经发现了越来越多非自然的思想作品
has uncovered more products of an unnatural mind.
你面前的这幅画
The drawings here before you
是在达芬奇的工作室里找到的
were found in Da Vinci's studio.
进一步说明了这个异教徒把男性的那个...
Notice the extent to which the deviant has detailed the male...
解剖得很细致
anatomy.
人类不是上帝凭想象创造出来的吗?
Was man not created in God's image?
上帝和艺术家相提并论? 我为你的联想感到震惊
Genesis, artista? I'm shocked you got that far.
如果不是因为热爱神圣 研究人类形态只是一个短语
Studying the human form is an expression, if not an adoration, of the divine.
嗯 嗯
Mm. Mm.
那这个笔记本说明了什么?
But then, what of this notebook?
在一个秘密小隔间找到的
Found in a secret compartment, no less.
搜索大师的工作室 太无耻了
Raiding the Maestro's workshop. That's the obscenity here.
请原谅证据的残破 因为...
Please excuse the condition of the evidence, for...
这很显然是被告为了不让他的异教徒信仰在这里被呈现出来
clearly the accused tried to prevent his heathen beliefs from being presented here
而把这笔记本烧了
by burning it.
人身上有一个动物的头
An animal head on human form.
一个异教上帝
A pagan god.
这不止一页...
And not just one...
还有很多
Dozens.
异教徒的崇拜
The adoration of a heretic.
这不是崇拜 而是一个艺术家的杰作
This is not worship but an artistic endeavor.
真的吗?
Really?
你是在指这些虚假的上帝是
Are you then suggesting that this false god is a commission
最近赞助你儿子的委员会成员吗?
for your son's most recent patron?
我认为这个异教徒不仅鸡奸 还在施展巫术
I submit that not only does this deviant practice sodomy, but sorcery.
因此我恳请法庭判处被告死刑
Thus I ask the court to consider no other sentence but death.
- 你太过分了  - 这不关你的事
- You've gone too far.  - This doesn't concern you.
瑞阿里奥伯爵明说了他们是对达芬奇有计划的
Count Riario made it very clear that he has plans for Da Vinci.
他想看到他被捕 而不是死
He wanted to see him arrested, not dead.
好吧 那由法庭来决定
Well, that's in the hands of the court.
如果当庭揭露你家里的风流韵事会怎么样?
What might the court say about your own family's erotic proclivities?
有谣言说你自己的妻子阿莱格拉
The rumors of your own wife, Allegra,
和一个帅气的男性化女佣有染
dallying with a strikingly mannish maidservant.
羞辱我的家人 请你后果自负 荡妇
Shame my family at your peril, harlot.
嗯 有本事就来吧
Mm. I welcome the invitation.
你似乎对一个你在法庭上谴责的男人感到异常烦恼
You seem oddly bothered about the fate of a man you denounced to the court.
如果你对控制我的力量还有忌惮之心的话
If you have any respect for the powers that command me,
就不会再提逼我写告发信的事了
you will never again mention forcing me to write the denunciation.
你太胆大了 阁下
You are reckless, Signor.
你让自己对美第奇家族的仇恨蒙蔽了自己的目的
You have let your hatred for the Medicis cloud your purpose.
而你是被自己的恐惧蒙蔽的
And your fear clouds yours.
我向你保证 女士
I assure you, Signora,
等洛伦佐和达芬奇不在了
when Lorenzo and Da Vinci are gone,
会有很多男人想填补你的空虚
there'll be plenty of cocks willing to fill your void.
这里再加点细节吧
Perhaps a bit more detail here.
- 阁下 这好看吗?  - 好看 很可爱
- How does this look, Excellency?  - Lovely. Very lovely.
朱利亚诺!
Giuliano!
你他妈的疯了吧?
Are you out of your fucking mind?
十日谈?
The Decameron?
我跟我弟弟说两句话 走开
I would have words with my brother. Away.
滚!
Away!
走 走 走
Go, go, go.
我让你帮忙重塑信誉
I asked you to help restore our reputation.
- 你让我展示魅力  - 他们都是虔诚的天主教徒
- You asked me to charm them.  - They are devoted Catholics.
你觉得他们对一部淫荡修女
How do you think they will respond to a play,
和饥渴神父比比皆是的剧目会作何反应?
that's wall to wall nun-sluts and horny priests?
- 下流! 粗俗!  - 这是佛罗伦萨的代表
- It's bawdy! It's vulgar!  - It's Florence.
当然粗俗! 人们就是喜欢这个
Of course it's vulgar! That's why people love it.
你要砍掉所有丢人的情节
You will cut every scene that is at all scandalous.
如果我们不能让斐迪南和伊莎贝拉开户
If we fail to secure Ferdinand and Isabella's accounts,
美第奇银行就完蛋了
the Medici Bank is finished.
再一次证明了你就是一堆没脑子的傻肉
Time again you prove to be nothing more than dead weight.
也许你应该把我也当成叛徒宰了
Well, perhaps you should mark me a traitor and have me killed as well.
就这一件事 你永远不可能比我强
This is one thing you were never better at.
鸡奸
Sodomy.
巫术
Sorcery.
向异教之神献祭
Offerings to a pagan god.
还有什么比这更重的罪行?
What crimes could be worse than these?
然而 根据庭审的秩序
Thus, by the order of this court,
被告... 如果承认了巫术的指控...
the accused... if convicted of the charge of sorcery...
就会被判火刑...
shall be burned at the stake...
直到他的灵魂从毁灭的身体中剥离
so that his eternal soul is separated from his perverted body.
在我们继续进行下一个程序前...
We grant the accused one day to confess and plead mitigation...
我们给被告一天时间认罪请求减刑
before we deliberate any further.
你要接受减刑 莱昂纳多
You must accept a plea, Leonardo.
如果你认罪 还有机会!
If you confess, there's a chance!
- 保护洛伦佐?  - 拯救你自己!
- To protect Lorenzo?  - To save yourself!
若是不让我帮你 你会死的
If you won't let me help you, you will die.
那样 你的羞耻也就扫清了
That's a clean end to your disgrace, then.
天啊! 你跟她一样惹人生气!
Oh, Christ! You are just as exasperating as she was!
她死了吗?
Is she dead?
没什么区别 她离开了
It makes no difference. She's gone.
我让你想起她了
I remind you of her.
所以你才不敢直视我
That's why you can't stand to look at me.
因为她离开你了
Because she left you.
你母亲是个平民
Your mother was a commoner.
她是个侍女
She was a servant girl.
像她那样的人不能离开我这样的人
People like her don't leave people like me.
不可以
They don't.
讲不通
It wouldn't make sense.
你身上的天赋真是浪费了
Genius was wasted on you.
你想要什么吗?
Do you want something?
嗯
Mm.
达芬奇会被判刑
Da Vinci faces imprisonment,
可能会被处死
perhaps death,
而你有办法跟治安官周旋
and you have the power to intercede with the magistrate.
那需要做出牺牲...
Not without certain sacrifices...
目前我们的贵宾很拘谨
given the prudery of my current guests.
他给我画的肖像很好
His portrait of me is remarkable.
可是如果不能完成的话 就不能让你想起我了
But it won't remind me of you nearly so well if it's never finished.
博蒂切利或者基尔兰达约可以接手
Botticelli or Ghirlandaio can take over.
你就为了这个要放掉艺术家?
Is that why you want the artista freed?
- 为了让自己名垂千古?  - 不是
- To immortalize you?  - No.
为了保护我们
To protect us.
达芬奇发明的天赋救过我们的命 洛伦佐
Da Vinci's gift for inventions saved our lives, Lorenzo.
他可以发明一个方法跳出窘境
Well, he can invent his way out of his dilemma.
晚安
Good night,
亲爱的
my dear.
嗯... 这些放大镜是当放大镜用的吗?
Um... does this periscope thing do what it's supposed to do?
我是按照说明办的 不过跟你们有一样的猜测
I followed the specifications but your guess is as good as mine.
他单子上的其它东西呢?
What about the other items on his list?
嗯 这罐浆糊溶解之前可以把一个人粘住好一阵
Um, this paste will hold a man for a good while before dissolving.
我给尼科试过这个药了 把他放翻了将近15分钟
I tested this potion out on Nico. Knocked him out for nearly 15 minutes.
你应该先告诉我 不然我摔倒的时候可能把脑袋摔坏了
You might have told me first. I could have split my head open when I collapsed.
有没有人能告诉我... 我们要粘谁 为什么要粘?
Can anyone tell me... who are we gluing to what and why?
是这样 我们的朋友可能在监狱里已经傻了
Look, our friend might have lost his wits in prison.
有这种情况
It happens.
捆绑架 迷药 放大镜
A prison, a potion, a periscope,
一头猪还有浆糊
a pig and a paste pot.
要是有个疯子造出来个抓动物的陷阱 应该就是这个样子了吧
If a madman created a scavenger hunt, this is what it would look like.
你觉得自己比我们都聪明 艺术家
You thought you could outsmart us all, artista.
可是上帝比你聪明
But God's wiser than you.
而且是站在我们这边的
And he's on our side.
- 现在呢?  - 等信号
- What happens now?  - We wait.
- 等干什么?  - 不知道
- For what?  - I don't know.
他说会很明显
He said it would be obvious.
- 怎么回事?  - 怎么了?
- What's going on?  - What is that?
我觉得这够明显了
I guess that's pretty clear.
达芬奇!
Da Vinci!
别放炮了
Stop the explosions.
怎么了?
What?
你觉得我是在牢房里策划了一次炮击吗?
You think I've organized a bombardment from my cell?
我从来不会停止取乐
I never cease to amaze myself.
哪来的?
Where are they coming from?
你还真是不着急过来
You took your time coming to visit.
你也就危急的时候会想到我了!
You want my company now, with your little prick on the line!
- 我们时间有限 琐罗  - 他们说的是真的吗? 这地方把你脑子整坏了?
- We have minutes, Zo.  - Is it true what they say? This place sours your brain?
- 你要帮我吗?  - 穿过厨房有一条出去的路
- Do you want to help me or not?  - There's a way out through the kitchens.
我们不能一起走 你要留下
We're not going together. You're staying.
- 才不要  - 听着...
- Fuck, no.  - Look...
不能让他们知道我越狱了
They can't know I've escaped.
要让他们认为我还在这
They need to think I'm still here.
带上吧 老鼠毛的
Wear that. It's rat's hair.
把我自己埋进蝙蝠屎里冒充你?
Cloak myself in bat shit and pretend I'm you?
对天发誓 我还没疯呢
I swear to God I'm not mad.
我只是绝望
I'm desperate.
愤怒 另外需要吃顿好的
Enraged. In need of a good meal.
不过我没疯
But I am not mad.
你还真是跟朋友不客气
You ask a great deal of your friends.
我知道
I know.
别打我主意
Sodomite.
所有人都在押 长官!
Everybody's still locked in, sir!
不管你朋友策划了什么 都失败了
Whatever your friends planned, it failed.
去你的 莱昂
Fuck you, Leo.
蝙蝠屎的磷化炸弹
Phosphorus bat shit bombs.
也许我是疯了
Maybe I am losing my mind.
计划就是大家一起被烧死?
So the grand plan is we all burn at the stake?
这是个简单直接的行动
It's a straightforward operation.
这是禁闭和中毒性疯癫的产物！彻底疯了!
It's the product of solitude and delirium! It's totally mad!
难道艺术不需要一点疯癫吗?
Doesn't certain art require a touch of madness?
我觉得你应该知道这东西只有在日光下才能工作的吧?
I suppose you are aware that this device can only function in the daylight?
- 我早有准备  - 你当然有
- I've prepared for that.  - Of course you have.
要是这招不奏效 你想过后果吗?
Have you given any thought to what will happen if it doesn't work?
- 没什么  - 我受惊了 又放心了
- None whatsoever.  - I'm both terrified and reassured.
我才不当别人的爪牙
I will be no-one's pawn.
他们把我放在众目睽睽之下取笑
They put me on display to be ridiculed,
作为鸡奸洛伦佐的工具
as a tool to sodomize Lorenzo.
他们夺走了我的自由
They took away my liberty.
要让他们也尝到跟我同样的境遇!
And now they will taste the same bile that I have!
而且...
Besides...
还有什么计划可以给我带来我渴望的东西?
what other plan gains me what I crave? Hm?
你渴望什么 莱昂?
Which is what, Leo?
治安官的屁股
The magistrate's arse.
在我们看演出之前 我给你们看过这个吗?
Before we head in to the performance, have I shown you this?
长凳?
A bench?
我们阿拉贡地区也有
We have benches in Aragon.
是 我知道 不过请注意...
Yes, yes, but please notice...
这边缘上面的标记
notice the markings along its edge.
每周一次 我都对想要见我的人开放我的书房
Once a week, I open my study to anyone who wishes to approach me
长凳上的标记显示了请求人排队的次序
and petitioners mark on the bench to indicate their place in line.
对下等人开放吗?
Doesn't that open you to rabble?
有时候 会的
On occasion, yes.
不过这也保持了佛罗伦萨的兴旺
But it also keeps Florence thriving.
就像古语说的 "金钱无罪"
As the old saying has it, "Pecunia non olet."
铜臭不臭
Money has no smell.
我们美第奇家族没有帕吉家族那么辉煌的历史
We Medicis have no historic name like the Pazzis.
我们只能依靠自己的智慧
We must rely on our wits.
我们改革 创造金融工具
We innovate. We create the financial instruments,
现在已经受整片大陆的依赖
on which the entire continent now relies.
美第奇家族的座右铭?
The motto of the house of Medici?
"敬神... 求利"
"In God... and profit."
而且这利润是看得见的
And that profit emerges from vision.
听着 家族血统还有头衔...
See, names and lineages and titles...
它们会消退 不过金钱...
they fade, but currency...
永远是金钱
currency stays current.
而且 比这片大陆上其它银行更出众的
And that, more than any other bank in the land,
是美第奇家族的专业性
is the expertise of the house of Medici.
这枚弗罗林正面有我们的印章...
This florin, with our seal on the front...
还有哪种货币是以城市命名的?
What other currency is named after a city?
只有佛罗伦萨是因为金融的成功而出名的
Only Florence is so identified with financial success,
堪称此种荣誉
to lay claim to that honor.
这里有一个新的世界...
There is a new world here...
就在佛罗伦萨
in Florence.
我等你们的决定
I await your decision.
我想知道他今晚的演员会不会像他这样高谈阔论
I wonder if his actors tonight will speechify quite like he does.
演员们 请注意
Players, attend.
今晚我们要演十日谈 不过不是全部的章节
We will be performing the Decameron this evening, but not all the parts.
我被劝告删掉所有章节 只保留最虔诚的部分
I've been counseled to remove all but the most pious pieces,
是为了我们皇室的贵宾
for the deference of our regal guests.
不过... 佛罗伦萨不是他们的家 是我们的
But... Florence is not their home. It's ours.
他们要是不喜欢就滚蛋
And they will either love it or leave.
准备好 我们的剧目只演出下流和粗俗的章节
Prepare our production so that only the bawdy and vulgar stories remain.
阁下 那你哥哥怎么办?
Excellency, what of your brother?
他会跟其他人一起笑抽的
He'll laugh his arse off with the rest of them.
- 这头猪呢 阁下?  - 留下
- And this pig, Signor?  - Stays in.
我们的城市里怎么就不能留一两头猪呢?
For what's our city without a pig or two?
今天怎么样?
How did it go today?
他们有好领袖心照不宣的特点
They have the tacit trait of all good leaders.
藏不住心里所想
Their faces belie nothing.
我不敢相信我们要接受这种堕落
I cannot believe we are to be subjected to such decadence.
衰落的制度戏剧化得抽打着他们的痛处
Dying regimes flail dramatically in their death throes.
而且请相信我 美第奇家族的制度也时日无多了
And trust me when I predict the days of the Medici regime are numbered.
晚上好
Buona sera.
今晚我们为你呈献佛罗伦萨的礼物
Tonight we give you a gift of Florence.
薄伽丘的十日谈
Boccaccio's the Decameron.
出于对您的尊重 我删除了部分剧目
As a favor to you, I've chosen not to present all the pieces.
一百个故事太长了
100 stories takes a long time,
我不想让前排的观众们
and I didn't want the poor souls in the front
被牧羊人毛里奇奥的味道熏晕了
to be smoked out by the stench of Maurizio the shepherd.
今晚你们将会见证佛罗伦萨的精髓
Now, this evening, you will witness the true spirit of Florence.
她的信仰和品德
Her faith and virtues,
还有她的自由和庸俗
right along with her freedom and vulgarities.
请欣赏... 十日谈
Enjoy... the Decameron.
哎呀 我把所有的钱都花在发带上了
Alas, I've used my last coin on ribbons for my hair.
让我买面包的阿姨肯定会生气的
The aunt who wanted bread will surely be angry with me.
我还能做什么?
Whatever am I to do?
哎呀...
Alas...
我在这条路上等了很久
I have wandered this road for many a day and night.
为了触摸女人的身体 我什么都愿意付出
What I would not give to touch a woman's flesh.
哦!
Ooh!
为什么我的腿突然这么无力
Why, I'd give my legs underneath me.
啊
Ah.
只有当圣阿里格让我触摸到她的时候
Only when Saint Arrigo's hand does touch her bones to mine,
才能治愈我
will I be healed in time.
也许我可以用尽我的力气试试
Perhaps I could try to lift with all my might.
如果你可以 我一定会抓紧的
And if you could, I'd surely hold on tight.
哦 啊!
Ooh. Argh!
这是什么...?
What's this...?
温柔的幽会需要合适的光线
A romantic assignation requires the appropriate light.
现在 你问过我 什么样的罪行会比鸡奸和巫术更重
Now, you asked me what crime could possibly be worse than sodomy or sorcery.
我从来不回避挑战
Well, I never turn down a challenge.
别动 别动
Be still. Be still.
不然你一动我朋友可能就提起性趣来了
Or my friend here may get aroused by your movements.
黏胶要粘好长一阵呢
The fixative will last a good while,
请仔细听吧
so listen closely.
因为你的名誉决定于此
Your reputation depends on it.
在这一组镜头最后面
At the far end of this arrangement of prisms and lenses,
是一个模糊相机
lies a camera obscura.
通常是凭借自然光线来投射影像的
It's usually employed to delight crowds with projections of nature.
不过非自然光线也可以
But unnatural projections work just as well.
- 你疯了  - 是
- You're insane.  - Yes.
现在收获我的破坏吧
Now reap the whirlwind.
上帝完成了所有的愿望...
God grants all wishes...
他们看不到你的脸
They cannot see your face.
目前还看不到
Yet.
我要做的只是调整几度焦距 再打开镜头
All I need to do is rotate you a few degrees, open the prism again,
你就将遗臭万年
and your notoriety will be assured for centuries.
- 你想怎么样?  - 你给我在四份文件上盖章
- What do you want?  - Your mark on four documents.
第一份 不可撤销的驳回所有对我的指控
One, an irrevocable dismissal of the charges against me,
以及对未来指控的赔偿文件
and indemnity against future prosecution.
第二份 对你自己兽奸罪行的公正悔过
Two, a full confession to your crime of bestiality in the palace of justice,
可以在我死之前完全保密
to be held in safekeeping in the event of my death.
第三份 为你所谓的庭审造成对达芬奇的折磨
Three, a donation of 50 florins to Piero da Vinci,
赔付五十弗罗林
for tolerating your so-called courtroom.
第四份 向我明示匿名告发的人
Four, the release to me of the secret denunciation which accused me.
火焰熄灭之前你要在四份文件上盖章
You will make your mark on all four documents before this flare dies,
不然我就打开镜头把你的罪行公之于众
or I will open the prism again and expose your vice for all to see.
我会告诉大家你的所作所为的!
I'll tell them what you've done!
你是想解释说这个现场
Your preferred explanation is that this entire scene,
是一个全佛罗伦萨都知道
was engineered in your inner sanctum,
被单独关押在禁闭室的人干的吗?
by a man that all Florence knows is in solitary confinement?
不会有人信的
The people will never believe it of me.
罪行越重 越吸引人
The more scandalous the accusation, the greater their appetite for it.
庭审我的时候旁听席里满是人
The gallery was filled at my trial,
而我只是一个疯癫的艺术家而已!
and I am just a mad artist!
对治安官的庭审应该就只剩下站席了
It'll be standing room only for a magistrate's trial.
而如果你违约
And should you renege on our agreement,
这块板子... 通过阿氏处理法
then this shroud... treated with silver nitrate,
使用硝酸银制作
using the methods of Albertus Magnus,
可以承载你的丑行很长时间
bears a lasting record of your infamy,
我会很高兴在未来展出
which I would be happy to display in the future.
就算你能说服人们
And even if you could convince people,
这个不是你
somehow that this isn't you,
你的余生都将用来
you will spend the rest of your life,
回应无尽的传言
answering the undying rumors.
因为人们相信自己的眼睛
Cos people believe what's before their eyes.
而我既然能让这幅图展现在佛罗伦萨的天空
And if I can get this image seen in the skies above Florence,
我就能让它无处不在
I can get it seen everywhere.
历史就会这样铭记你
This is how history will remember you.
在你的法庭上
Fucking a pig,
操一头猪
in the middle of your courtroom.
谎言 还是真相...
Lies, truth...
根本没关系
It's irrelevant.
只有最精彩的故事会传承
The best story wins.
光明带来了什么困惑
Oh, what confusion comes with light.
请赐予我夜的黑暗
Bring me the darkness of the night.
太多不可见 太多未知
So much unseen, so much to know.
在黑暗中 才会出现最好的惊喜
In the dark, the best surprise does show.
多么激动的场面 阁下
A hysterical spectacle, Your Excellency.
空中的图像 我从来没见过
The image in the sky. I've never seen anything like it.
剧场是... 神奇的
Theatre is... magic.
就是这样!
That it is!
干得好 各位 干得漂亮!
Well done, everyone. Well done!
被告被指控关于...
The defendant stands accused of...
鸡奸和异教的罪名
deviancy and heresy.
经过考虑 庭审程序
After due consideration, it is the ruling of this court,
诉方无法证实罪名成立
that the prosecution was unable to prove these crimes true.
我在此解除对莱昂纳多・达芬奇的所有指控
I hereby dismiss all charges against Leonardo da Vinci.
- 我是个天才  - 你还一身蝙蝠屎味儿
- Well, I'm a genius.  - You still smell like bat shit.
好哇!
Ah, bravo!
好啊 莱昂
Bravo, Leo.
你应该祝贺的是他
That's the man you should be congratulating.
我不知道你怎么做到的
I don't know how you did that,
不过在拥有自由的时候 好好享受吧
but enjoy your freedom while you may.
罗马不能通过法庭达到的目的
For what Rome cannot accomplish through the courts,
会换别的方式来的
it will by other means.
别惹麻烦
Stay out of trouble.
父亲...
Father...
我会的
I will.
你的路永远不会平坦
Your path has never been easy.
在我的土地 力量都是与生俱来的
In my land, power derives from birthright.
为了保持家族的力量
I had to marry my pug-faced cousin,
我不得不娶我那个狗脸的表妹
to keep power in the family.
不过你和你弟弟
But you and your brother,
并没有皇室血统
with no royal blood at all,
可以组建一整座城市
rally an entire city.
不用恐怖统治 而是欢乐
Not out of fear, but joy.
你们甚至知道人民的名字
You even know some of them by name.
人民也因此拥戴你
And they love you for it.
你给我留下了印象
You've left your mark on me.
我也会在佛罗伦萨留下我的印象
And I leave my mark in Florence.
我们同意你的条款
We agree to your terms.
美第奇家族将会是新西班牙使用的银行
The Medicis will be the bankers of a new Spain.
敬佛罗伦萨 同性恋可以和任何人 随时随地 不受拘束
To Florence, where you can bugger whoever, wherever, and get away with it.
敬使这成为可能的朋友
To the friends who make it possible.
说真的 我很高兴有你这个朋友
Seriously, I'm lucky to have you.
等你帮我从屁股里洗蝙蝠屎的时候也别忘了就行
Remember that when you're washing the bat shit from my arse crack.
如果我在庭审上展示这个 就不会有那么多的诡辩可以救得了你了
If I'd produced this at the trial, no amount of sophistry would have saved you.
不过我只是想让你曝光 不想让你死
But I wanted to see you exposed, not killed.
为什么?
Why?
因为你跟女人之间的不是真爱
What you have with women isn't love.
你是因为恐惧才找女人的
You're with them out of fear.
我这是自然天性的好奇
I'm curious by nature.
欲望... 并不只是喜欢哪个性别那么简单
Desire... It's not as simple as one sex or the other.
抱歉 我伤害了你
I'm sorry I hurt you.
我的实验和好奇心 太过...
My experiments and curiosities, they're...
有时候是有代价的 我本该多加小心
They're not always without cost and I should mind that better.
不过相信我... 相信我...
But trust me... trust me...
没有人能管我
no-one defines me.
不管是佛罗伦萨过时的法律
Not Florence's outdated laws,
而且当然...
and certainly...
当然... 你也不行
certainly... not you.
你对我的感情会消退 也会再找到别人去爱
Your infatuation will fade and you will find others to love.
我不怀疑
I have no doubt.
每一个吻都有意义
Every kiss sends a message.
这个吻... 即是告别
That one... was goodbye.
告别?
Goodbye?
是这样 这个曲调从没听别人哼过
Do you know, I've never heard that tune from anyone except you.
我小的时候我父亲经常哼唱
My father used to hum it to me when I was a child.
好了
Done.
他现在在哪?
Where is he now?
我不能说
I cannot say.
失去父母很让人伤心
Losing a parent breaks hearts.
我的父亲对我来说一直是...
My father's always been...
迷失的
lost to me.
那你母亲呢?
And your mother?
在隔海相望的 一块没有名字的土地上
In a land with no name, across the seas.
如果我收集的线索是真的
If the clues I've gathered on my quest are true.
脱离这次告发 也许我就能再找到她
Escaping that denunciation, perhaps I can find her again.
你怎么得到的?
How did you come by this?
这些告发信通常都是被严密看管的
These denunciations are usually so well guarded.
嗯 我对被严密看管的东西...
Mm. Well, I have a penchant for acquiring things...
都有强烈的获取倾向
that are well guarded.
你计划怎么办呢?
And what do you plan on doing with it?
嗯?
Hm?
我计划通过它来找到并面对我的告发者
I plan on using it to find and confront my accuser.
显然是
Obviously.
不管是谁写的 都差点断送了我的自由和性命
Cos whoever wrote those words almost took my freedom and my life.
要是告发者并没有想让事情这么严重呢?
And what if your accuser didn't intend for it to go that far?
他们还能有什么期望?
What other outcome could they have intended?
- 这可是鸡奸的罪名  - 我知道
- It was a sodomy charge.  - I know.
我凭借胆识和智慧才摆脱的
I only got out with nerve and wit.
嗯
Hm.
这个是与我很亲近的人送的
That belonged to someone very dear to me.
嗯?
Hm?
给
Here.
带着吧 小心保管以防不测
Carry it with you. Keep it safe in case anything happens.
为什么你会发生不测?
Why would anything happen to you?
因为天有不测风云
Because these are uncertain times.
我能向洛伦佐炫耀吗?
And shall I flaunt it near Lorenzo?
那可能会引起不测
That would alleviate any uncertainty.
你要是聪明就不会这么做的
You'd be wise not to.
你恋爱过吗... 女士?
Have you ever been in love... Signora?
嗯...
Um...
在我的追求中 爱只是负担
In my pursuits, love is a liability.
我也是
Mine, too.
也许这就是我们的共同点
Maybe that's what we share.
什么?
What?
我们都注定一生无爱
Both of us bound to a life without love.
你看起来有点意外
You seem surprised.
我告诉过你 一旦你饮过记忆之泉我就会回来
I told you I would return once you had sipped from the fountain of memory.
可我没有
But I haven't.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
你在监狱里没有遇到什么吗?
You did not experience something while imprisoned?
那只是一个梦
That was a dream.
仅此而已
It was nothing more.
当然 你全都记得
Surely you, who remembers all,
须知这不是梦
know it was no dream.
什么都不是
It was nothing.
只是...
It was just...
只是一闪而过 偶发...
Just flashes. Incoher...
闭上眼睛再看一遍
Close your eyes and see again.
回到洞里 莱昂纳多
Return to the cave, Leonardo.
有尸体 我看到尸体
There were bodies. I saw bodies.
我看... 我看到一个人...
I s... I saw a man...
被倒吊着
hanging upside down.
我...
I...
我觉得... 我觉得他跟别人一样 已经死了
I thought... I thought he was dead, like the rest.
不过他还活着
But he was alive.
- 他是谁 莱昂纳多?  - 我...
- Who was it, Leonardo?  - I...
放开我
Free me.
放开我!
Free me!
- 不可能  - 你看到了什么?
- It doesn't make sense.  - What did you see?
放开我
Free me.
是我自己
It was me.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/ ==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：潇妹纸
时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：竺 浅浅 碟子
校对：竺 影子